# Siddharth Desai

Location: Broomfield, CO 80021| Phone: 908-883-0191 | Email: <a href="mailto:shdesai118@gmail.com">shdesai118@gmail.com</a> Portfolio: <a href="https://shd118.github.io/Portfolio/">https://github.com/SHD118\_LinkedIn:</a> <a href="https://github.com/in/siddharth-desai-379040193/">https://github.com/in/siddharth-desai-379040193/</a>

#### FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Passionate and skilled individual with experience in web development, software and systems engineering for Utilities and Defense industries. Exceptional experience in leading project teams, working closely with stakeholders and customers. Experience with CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, and Node.js.

### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and Node.js, Java, C#, SQL, bash

Libraries: Bootstrap, Moment.js, jQuery, UiKit, and Node

**Applications**: GitHub

# **PROJECTS**

GameGo https://github.com/mthurber82/videogameapp

Leveraged rawg.io and youtube server-side API's to fetch video game data and a corresponding video of the game. The results were displayed using CSS framework UIKIT, JavaScript, and jQuery.

Work Scheduler | https://github.com/SHD118/Work-Scheduler

Created a helpful planner to keep track of daily tasks. Dynamically created html/css elements through Jquery and javascript. Used Moment.js to keep track of the current time and leveraging bootstrap to create a user friendly webpage

Coding Quiz | https://github.com/SHD118/coding-challenging-quiz

Developed a coding quiz using CSS, JavaScript, and jQuery where user's test scores are saved in the browser's local storage. Worked with data structures such as arrays and objects

#### **EXPERIENCE**

**PSEG: Technology Engineer** 10/2019 - present

Project: Filenet-ECM - (2019 - present)

- Full application support and server maintenance of Enterprise content management environment, which includes Roxi, BPF, Guidance link, and Sox.
- Researching and facilitating the development of new ECM approaches driving process improvement and techniques for successful implementation as required as well as monitoring, auditing, troubleshooting, and updating functions for ECM software, systems or products

Project: Filenet-McLaren - (2019 - present)

- Full application support and server maintenance of McLaren Enterprise Sweep while collaborating with multiple IT teams for server patching
- Implemented, tested changes, new builds and upgrades in Dev, Q/A environment, and scheduled for rollout to production

## **Lockheed Martin: Software Engineer** 01/2016 - 12/2019

*Project: Automated Regression Testing/Cross Product Team — (2016 – 2018)* 

- Interfaced with clients of the automation and software teams to define system requirements
- Developed new automation tools and procedures to test Aegis Weapon System components
- Facilitated in creating an automated locating tool using computer vision techniques and robot framework
- Set up a virtual environment using Virtual Box and Vagrant to run automated test on a Jenkins Server
- Adapted rapidly to new operating and development environments that utilized Red Hat Linux, Python, Sikuli, Virtual Machines and shell scripting
- Created a Test Driver in Python that used keyword testing to Map to the correct Test
- Created Desktop Procedures and project artifacts for future and fellow Engineers to reference
- Lead in creation of automated test and helped analyze the pros and cons of cost

### **EDUCATION**

University Denver (DU), Denver, CO 08/2021 – present Full Stack Developer Certificate New Jersey Institute of Technology (NJIT), Newark, NJ 09/2011 – 12/2015 B.A. Computer Science